♪ In the not too distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday AD ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different from you or me ♪
♪ He worked at Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face in a red jump suit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses didn't like him
so they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit and watch them all ♪
♪ Then we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies begin or end ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Because he used those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
- Pan left.
♪ Gypsy ♪
- Hi, girl.
♪ Tom Servo ♪
- What a cool guy.
♪ Crow ♪
- A wisecracker.
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself,
"It's just a show ♪
♪ "I should really just relax" ♪
♪ For Mystery Science Theater 3000 ♪
- Exactly what I mean.
- Oh, okay, I'm up to speed so far.
Your point is that Big Bird
cannot be considered a puppet
because of his or her, uh, its size.
- Right, right.
The size and don't forget the feet.
Once a puppet has feet,
it ceases being a puppet
and starts being a costume.
- Well, what about Topo Gigio?
He was a puppet with feet.
- Oh, give me a break.
If you want to get technical,
Lambchop had feet, too.
Topo Gigio was an Italian
black art rod puppet.
Come on, Crow, that's a subcategory.
- Oh, look who's arguing semantics now!
- Hi, everybody. Welcome
to the Satellite of Love.
I'm Joel Robinson.
Looks like we've stumbled upon the robot's
weekly ontological discussion
about the nature of puppets.
- And the symbiotic relationship to man.
- Right, and their symbiotic
relationship to man.
Let's watch the fireworks.
- See?
- All right, if you're so smart,
what would you call H. R. Pufnstuf?
- Oh, that's a costume.
Remember the puppet paradigm.
Feet plus inarticulated
mouth means costume.
- What about Yoda?
- Well, Yoda was a humanly articulated
floating armature creature
used in combination with
radio contorted servos
and (mutters).
- What about puppet or
costume, Tom? Come on!
- All right, ya got me, I don't know.
- See? I rest my case.
Okay, here's one for you.
What would you call Señor Wences,
the ventriloquist who built his career
out of talking to his hand?
- I call that a cry for help.
- Interesting.
- Mm-hmm.
(upbeat theme music)
- Okay, if you two are ready, lets begin.
- Here's a quick pop
quiz on the many varied
celebrity puppets in show
business past and present,
and I want you to define the genus
of each of these characters I list.
We'll begin with some
characters from television.
Cambot, keep score and watch the clock.
Ready? Let's begin.
Rowlf the dog, Crow?
- Uh, puppet?
- Puppet, yeah, could
you be more specific?
Tom Servo.
- Muppet.
- Right, exactly.
- Okay, next, Meow Meow Kitty.
Crow?
- Uh, puppet?
- Uh, what kind of puppet?
- Uh, hand?
- Yes, and?
- Uh, lame hand puppet.
- Yes, yes, very good!
Okay, next.
- I knew that.
- Kukla.
- Oh boy, this is tough.
- Oh, Kukla, Kukla.
- Kukla or Ollie, I'll take either one.
- Oh, oh, oh, I know that!
- Crow?
- Uh, hard shell head, soft cloth body
hand puppet with sock sleeve coverlet!
- Very good, I thought you were
out of the running for that one.
Now these next are going
to get a little bit harder.
Okay, let's continue.
Spitting Image.
- Oh, oh, outrageous and wickedly funny
foam and latex puppets.
- Okay, correct.
DC Follies.
- Uh, shameless Sid
and Marty Kroft ripoff.
- Very, good.
(dinging)
Ooh, the Mads are calling.
- Ooh!
- Hello, button.
Let's slam straight away
into this week's invention exchange.
- Big noses!
- Uh, that's right, the super schnoz.
(speaks in foreign language)
- What?
- Big noses!
- Right, right, uh,
Durante, eat your heart out.
Big honkers.
- Comin' at ya!
- In 3D!
(sniffing)
Do I smell pie in the oven?
- Uh, not in this building.
Say, Doctor, sports scent tonight?
- Well, what's the point
of the big noses anyway?
- Well, they're just really big, you know?
Just think of the stuff
you could do with 'em.
- Very useful.
Now I can brown nose myself.
- Wow, you and I are kinda
on the same wavelength.
I thought of my invention exchange
as being this big head.
♪ Who's that guy with the big head ♪
- Hey, Joel, can you
help me with my algebra?
- Sure, no problem, it's a
snap with my new big head.
- Say, Joel, do people make fun of you
now that you have a big head?
- Oh, sure, people are naturally curious,
but then I explain to them that
I've got a really big head.
- Uh, Joel, are you in any pain?
- No, just a really big head.
- Oh.
- So I guess we can say that you got
a big head there, huh?
- Yup, you can.
(Crows whistles)
- Big as all outdoors.
- It's real big, sirs.
What do you think?
- I knew a man in Chicago
once that had a big head.
Uh, no, it was nowhere near that big.
- Uh, Doctor, I don't
mean to stick my nose
into your business.
(chuckling)
But shouldn't we really
be getting to the movie?
- Right you are, my long-nosed companion.
Joel, your experiment
this week is going to be
like biting down on a
double-edged razor blade.
- It's called Fugitive Alien II,
and it's every bit as stanky as part one.
- Send him the movie, Frank.
- Oh no, we got big head!
(alarm buzzing)
♪ Who's that fella with the big head ♪
♪ Big head, talkin' big ♪
- Hey, this is Sandy Frank.
This is Sandy Frank on drugs.
Any questions?
(Tom chuckles)
- [Tom] Uh-oh, Fugitive
Alien II, Electric Boogaloo.
The Heretic, Nerds in
Paradise, On the Move,
Citizens on Patrol.
- [Joel] Star Force times two.
Two times the action,
two times the confusion!
- [Tom] Badoom! (chuckles)
(trumpeting music)
Love this music.
- Please remain seated
until the building has
come to a complete stop.
(Tom trumpets along with music)
- [Joel] McMlxxvi?
He's the Scottish guy
in charge of copyright.
- [Tom] Yeah, copyright.
Yeah, that's right.
Hey, this music is perky!
(perky music)
I'm feeling really good.
- Yeah!
Woo!
- Woo!
- Hey, this is gonna be fun
guys, I'm feelin' really,
ah, who are we kiddin'?
This is a Fugitive Alien sequel.
We're in for the two most
painful hours of our lives.
(Tom sobs)
- [Joel] Come on, you
guys, we gotta be strong.
Try not to fall apart.
Come on, we've been through
to too many Sandy Frank films
together to let him defeat us now.
- [Narrator] A thousand light years away
from our solar system lies Valna star--
- [Tom] We know.
- [Narrator] A mysterious planet
with an enriched atmosphere which imparts
super human strength--
- Seen it.
- [Tom] Taped it. (sobs)
- [Narrator] Valna star
is ruled by Lord Halkon,
an evil genius who has
created a race of warriors,
the Star Wolves.
- Neat.
- [Narrator] On a mission
of destruction to earth,
Star Wolf Ken is ordered to kill a child.
His refusal starts a fight
which results in the
death of his best friend.
- [Tom] Uh-huh, uh-huh.
- [Narrator] As punishment,
Ken is set adrift
in outer space.
- And forced to watch this film.
- [Narrator] But Ken is found and rescued
by the crew of the earth
spaceship Bacchus 3.
(bots growl)
And soon he becomes a member of the crew.
Ken's girlfriend Rita has been sent
to find and destroy him,
but it is she who is subsequently killed.
- In goofy scenes like this.
- It was you who fired that shot.
It was you.
- [Tom] Yeah, so?
What of it?
- Rita!
- Meter maid!
(heroic music)
- Hey!
- Ho-ho!
- [Joel] My chick's dead!
Ay!
- [Tom] Woo.
- [Narrator] Only one
memory of Rita remained,
her golden Valma medallion.
- [Tom] Which Ken hocked
for a pack of cigarettes.
- [Narrator] Ken will never forget her.
- [Joel] Or the Visa bill she ran up, huh?
- [Tom] Oh, it's over then.
- [Joel] Amen.
- Is it A-men or ah-men?
- [Narrator] Now Ken
and his earth comrades
are off in quest of new adventure.
Their mission, to fly to Saysar,
find a secret weapon, and destroy it.
- [Tom] And hopefully
do a little shopping.
- Let's have a look at that wound, Ken.
Oh, good, it's healing beautifully.
(Crow gasps)
Okay?
- [Tom] Hey, remember this?
♪ I love Ken, he is my friend ♪
♪ And I love Ken ♪
♪ I love Ken he is my sweet friend ♪
- You always tell me,
"Bear it like a man."
- Ah, come on, Dan, your
problem is you're jealous!
(laughing)
(Joel laughs mockingly)
- That's rich.
- Quit teasing.
- Okay.
- Yeah, terrific.
♪ I love Ken, he is my sweet friend ♪
♪ And I love Ken ♪
- Cut it out.
- There's something peculiar about him.
- [Joel] Mm-hmm!
That's good blow, mm-hmm!
- [Man] Top experts in
advanced defense technology.
- You heard right.
- Uh-huh.
- [Man] And you probably know all about
that secret weapon Caysar is said to have
imported from another planet.
- [Tom] Pretty much.
- There any truth to
those rumors, Colonel?
- [Dan] They say it could
blow up the universe.
- [Tom] Or worse!
- Where did you hear that?
- (chuckling) Well,
you know, occasionally,
I tune into the intergalactic grapevine.
(laughing)
(mock laughing)
- Captain Joe--
- [Joel] Shut up.
- I take it
you're trying to enlist my cooperation
for a mission you're about to--
(Joel and bots grunt)
Before I say yes or no,
I'll need to know more
about your intentions.
- [Rocky] I'll love you
all the days of my life.
- I don't know whatever gave you the idea
we're planning a mission.
We're just out for a ride.
A little excursion to discover more facts
about our universe.
(Joel chuckles)
- You don't say.
And how do I know I can trust you?
This Ken fellow seems
mighty suspicious to me.
- (chuckles) Ken's just a bit of a loner.
If you want, I'll call him in,
and you can talk to himself.
- Ken's a loaner?
How long before your Ken is fixed?
(Tom chuckles)
- [Joe] Ken?
Tammy?
I want to see you.
- [Joel] Oh, great, he
found out about the keg.
- [Tom] Plot point right there.
Hm?
- This is a girl officer's insignia.
- [Tom] Say.
- How did you get it?
- Through a lot of hard work
and a lot of pancake makeup.
- When you were sleeping,
I heard you call a girl's name out loud.
- [Tom] When I put your
hand in warm water.
- Rita, I think.
I believe that was it.
Does the name Rita mean anything to you?
- [Joel] Uh, it's a Beatles song?
- Ken!
- [Rocky] This is our present position.
Pegasus R2, IS4, right here.
- Here's the Spencer Gifts.
- Distance to Saysar is a rollatime.
- [Joel] A rolla-who?
- [Tom] Rolodex.
- Two-one-three, sir.
- Course three-seven is perfectly safe.
It's when we switch to course T
that we're likely to run into trouble.
There's a huge black hole
near R-five-by-nine--
- [Joel] And a vicious
dog laying to the left.
- Black hole, huh?
- Oh, neat.
- It swallows up anything that
comes up anywhere near it.
(Joel mimics scrubbing)
I don't think we can risk it.
- [Tom] Oh look, another
painting by Judy Chicago.
Now back to our movie.
- This puts a new light on
the conditions of our mission.
- A black light.
- The odds against success
are extremely high.
- [Tom] But then, I'm
extremely high. (chuckles)
- On the other hand, if we've gotta go,
I can't think of a better way.
- Huh?
- That's not funny, sir.
- I'll say it isn't.
I don't want to vanish in thin air.
When my time comes, I
want to go out in glory.
- [Joel] I want to be
torn apart my animals!
- Spoken like a true
woman, and a naive one.
- Naive yourself!
- Me so silly!
(laughing)
- Captain Joe, you don't necessarily
have to get swallowed up in a black hole.
- [Tom] But it helps.
- If you chart your course carefully,
you can go through a tunnel
out to a white hole and safety.
It's a tricky maneuver.
- [Tom] Turkey?
- Where did you hear that?
- Where did I hear it?
I'm afraid I don't remember.
I guess it was at one of those
scientific briefings I attended.
- [Joel] Yeah, at my
aunt's house or somethin'.
- [Colonel] Ken, wait!
- You're walking down someone's throat!
(Colonel chuckles)
- [Joel] Wait a second, I
didn't tell you the punchline.
- Little slip of the tongue and you gave
your whole game away, didn't you?
- Yup.
- I don't understand.
- Do you find me pleasing?
- I know for a fact that only
a handful of Wolf attackers
have ever made it through a black hole
and still lived to tell the tale.
I only had to put two and two together
to realize you're a Star Wolf.
- [Tom] Who are you to judge?
Huh?
(Colonel grunts)
- Don't be a fool, Ken, I'm the
only friend you've got here!
(grunts)
- What's up?
What's going on?
- It's all my fault.
- [Tom] Yeah, he was just showing him
where his larynx was.
- I foolishly made a sarcastic
remark about earthlings.
Ken was right to act as he did.
Ill-chosen words have
been known to start wars.
- Yeah, the Sarcasm Wars of 1999.
- [Joel And Tom] Mm.
(Colonel chuckles)
- What a dipstick.
- I don't like that guy.
And I don't like you, either.
- [Ken] The feeling is mutual, Rocky.
- [Tom] Oh, Rocky, who do you like?
- [Dan] Captain!
Come up here, quick!
- Here he comes.
- Surprise!
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
- Look at that, sir.
What do you make of it?
- Ah, it's one of those nut clusters.
- [Rocky] Looks like a meteorite.
Quite a big one.
- Yeah, just one thing's wrong,
I don't see it on any chart.
- [Rocky] By the time
they get it on the chart,
it'll probably have broken up.
- [Joel] Like most rock bands, huh?
- [Tom] Oh, good one.
(Crow laughs)
- [Joel] Yeah, I speak the truth.
- You bet.
- Amen.
- Looks like we're getting
into hostile territory.
We have to be on our guard.
Rocky, take the controls.
- Again?
- Hurry, back to your station.
- [Rocky] Yes, sir.
- [Tom] Rocky, you hate Ken,
Ken, you make goofy faces,
Tammy, you love Rocky.
Uh, or Ken.
- Colonel Yurulin, that's your seat there.
- But, Captain--
- He said sit down.
- [Joel] But he didn't say Simon says!
- [Tom] He said Captain says.
Oh, wait a minute, which is moving?
The stars or the ship?
- Um, the stars?
- [Joel] Pink Floyd on the headphones,
set the controls for the heart of the sun.
- It's broccoli!
I hate broccoli.
- [Joel] You know, he's
got Kristy McNichol cheeks,
you know, when you look at him?
- I don't like this at all.
- Ken.
- Yes, sir.
- Destroy the meteorite
with the forward laser.
- Okay!
- Yes, sir!
(zapping)
♪ Love, love, love ♪
(upbeat theme music)
- Captain Joe, we're still alive!
That's the only thing that counts.
- [Joel] No, cleanliness is
the only thing that counts!
- I won't feel safe while he's alive.
- Kill him.
- What do you think you're doing?
- We've got a mission to accomplish.
I'm just going to remove an obstacle.
- [Joel] Your eyebrow.
- Ken, stop him!
If he kills me, you're next!
- [Ken] Easy, Rocky.
This isn't the right moment.
- Out of my way.
- Rocky, hold your fire.
- Again?
- I'm sorry to say we still need him.
- Need him for what?
- We rescued him to guide us
to Saysar and he'll do it.
Lock him up.
- Rack 'em up.
- Whatever you say.
- I just hope you know what you're doing.
- [Tom] I just want to
say your makeup sucks.
- As long as this guy's traveling with us,
our mission is threatened.
- [Joel] We'll never make it to Woodstock!
- [Tom] Huh? Huh?
- Huh?
- Oh, well.
- Hey, hey, ho, ho!
- Huh-huh-huh-ho!
(grunts)
(Joel and bots growl)
- Well, here you are.
It isn't the royal suite,
but it'll just have to do.
- [Tom] You want room service, dial nine.
There's a mint on the pillow.
- I need some towels!
- Listen to me!
If you want to make it
to Saysar in one piece,
you need me to guide you!
Any minute now we'll be
going by Demeter star.
It'll set us on fire!
Let me out, let me out!
- [Joel] I'm gonna hold my
breath till I turn blue!
Oh, I'm already,
oh, I did it again, I'm already blue.
- [Tom] Zinged yourself there. (chuckles)
(Tom hums)
(grunting)
- Huh?
- [Tom] Diarrhea is like
a storm raging inside you.
(groans)
- [Joel] I'm comin', Elizabeth!
- [Tom] Ooh!
- He's hallucinating split ends.
(Tom sings along with score)
- [Tom] Huh?
Oh, (chuckles) who am I tryin' to kid?
I'm not sick.
(ship whooshes)
(Crow mimics whooshing)
- [Joel] Mm-hmm, that's good amyl!
Ho, ho!
- What's the cabin temperature?
- [Tom] It's hotter than
my great aunt's apartment.
- 26.
- Tenperature?
(Tom chuckles)
- That seems a bit high.
- [Joel] Sunny side? Of the street?
- It's even hotter outside.
- (grunts) That calls for a drink.
- I'll go check it out.
- Ken.
- Huh?
- Wait a minute.
Look at that star.
- You look at that. I'm bitter.
(foreboding music)
- I don't get it.
That star, why, that's Demeter star.
- [Tom] Oh, it should
be bigger than a meter.
- How'd we get here?
It isn't on our course.
- [Tom] Hm.
Hm.
- Look at this, we're just drifting, sir!
Saysar isn't anywhere near here!
- Wow.
- We'll have to correct our course.
Switch over to seven-three-oh.
- Oh, what is that, traffic information?
(Tom chuckles)
(grunting)
- It won't move!
There's something wrong!
- [Tom] Yeah, it's this
movie, it sucks. (chuckles)
- [Ken] We must be caught
in Demeter's magnetic field!
All the controls are blocked!
(growling)
- [Tom] Uh-oh.
- [Joel] Man, if it's not
one thing, it's another.
Honey, I'm gonna be very late.
- [Joe] I've gotta see you right away.
It's an emergency.
- Again?
- Rocky?
- [Tom] He shouldn't spend too much time
away from the bathroom.
(groaning)
(grunting)
- [Joel] Oh, could you Armorall my suit?
- Rocky.
- Again?
- Rocky!
- [Tom] (chuckles) That's good, Crow.
(beeping)
- Captain!
- I scored another game!
- We're back to normal!
- All engines at full thrust.
- Engines full thrust!
- [Joel] That's full thrust?
- Yeah, big deal.
- Lame.
- [Tom] What luck, huh?
- [Joel] Looks like an aerosol can.
- I don't feel right about this at all.
- [Crow] You and me both, pal.
You and me both.
- Something suspicious.
We'd better get out of here
or be roasted alive.
- [Tom] Ah.
Huh?
Oh, Rocky, no.
On the paper, boy!
Come on.
- It was the salmon mousse.
(bots grunting)
- [Joe] Rocky, what's wrong?
- [Joel] Oh, Rocky cubed it.
(grunting)
- Pants too tight!
I'm--
- Sir.
- Turning Japanese!
- I've got this pain in my back.
- [Tom] I really think so.
- My--
- What?
- Rocky.
- I'm feeling dizzy!
- [Joe] Ken, take over.
- Yes, sir.
- Captain!
- Ooh!
- [Tom] She's looked better, hasn't she?
(chuckles)
- Tammy, it's all right.
- [Tammy] Captain, help me!
- [Joel] Oh, come on, you
kids are just overtired.
You're fighting sleep.
Now I want you to go to bed.
(Tom mimics crying)
Come on, come on.
- Those are just the after effects
of the ultra high speed we needed
to get through the black hole.
You'll just have to sleep it off.
I'll get you some medication.
- For me, too, sir.
- [Tom] All right, me, too!
- This'll relieve the pain.
- Take it.
- [Rocky] Sir?
- [Joe] Yeah?
- Are you sure you'll be all right?
You went through the black hole, too.
- [Joel] I'll be fine, I got
my friend Jack to help me.
(Tom chuckles)
What, is he in an automat?
- It looks like it.
- Check it out.
- [Tom] Oh, chicken salad,
grab me a chick sal.
- What's the matter?
Can't anyone hear me?
- [Tom] Sure.
- It's so hot.
Where is all this heat coming from?
- [Tom] No, you see, it's not
the heat, it's the humidity.
You see, the comfort index says--
- Listen to me!
I've got something important to tell you!
- [Joel] I'm the unsinkable Molly Brown!
- [Tom] Think they could
make bigger doors. (chuckles)
- Well, sir, how are they doing?
- Okay.
I gave them something to calm them down.
They're just gonna have to sleep it off.
- [Joel] I do that a lot.
(groans)
- Still awfully hot in here.
- Yeah, turn up the AC.
- I know.
- Captain, we really ought to move away
as quickly as we can.
I think we oughta boost to the engines.
- Hm.
- [Tom] Nothin'.
(engines bang)
(beeps)
- [Joel] Uh, curly fries are up, sir!
(dramatic, worrying music)
- [Tom] Hm? Well, at least
they spelled speed right.
(Tom chuckles)
- Engine trouble.
- [Tom] Ah, I told you to check the oil.
Didn't we fill it up in Auclair?
- Okay, I'll take her up.
- Those daring young men
in their jaunty jalopies!
(Tom sings along with music)
- [Joel] What is with you, sir?
Did you eat those radishes again?
- Captain, what's the matter?
- [Tom] Huh?
- [Ken] Dan, wake up!
- [Tom] Wake up, you're
late for cram school!
- Rocky, Rocky!
- Again?
- You gotta wake up!
You gotta wake up!
Rocky!
- [Tom] Ah, jeez, he's been
reading Bukowski again.
- Let me out of here!
- Hm?
- [Yurulin] Let me out of here!
- [Joel] Oh, phooey.
- [Tom] Wah, wah, wah.
- We have no time for you now!
You just stay in here and
stop all that yelling.
- Yeah, you'll just have to hold it.
- Haven't you noticed this heat?
What's causing it?
I want to know exactly where we are.
- Enough of your questions!
Be quiet.
I'll just have to get back to you later.
- [Crow] Bye!
- Listen to me!
Pay attention!
We mustn't get near Demeter star!
- Why not?
This heat's coming from the engines.
- You little fool.
- You little minx!
- Don't you realize the Demeter
star is about to explode?
- What's that?
- [Joel] Really?
He never said anything about--
- [Tom] Oh, looks like
Captain Joe is drunk again.
For those of you playing along at home,
in Fugitive Alien I,
Captain Joe was portrayed
as quite the drinkin' man. (chuckles)
Now this.
(groans)
- [Joel] Ooh.
- [Tom] I kinda feel like
him of all of a sudden.
(Joe groans)
No, I'll be okay, I'm fine.
(coughs) Something I ate, I think.
- [Joe] Ahh.
(door opens)
(Tom bubbles)
- Captain!
- Focus. Focus!
- [Rocky] Help me get him off the floor.
(groans)
- [Tom] Ah, oh.
Could you wipe my brow?
- [Joel] You don't look
very good, you know?
- [Tom] My left arm is a
little numb, I don't know.
- Guess it must have been a--
- [Tom] Ah, I'm fine.
Ah, so (clears throat)--
- High speed.
- Captain!
- What's going on here?
- Yurulin?
Who let you out?
- Captain listen to me!
- [Tom] Mm-hmm.
- You don't realize what's going on!
This sort of heat is only generated
by a star that's about to die.
That's what's happening to Demeter,
and we've gotta get out of here!
- Oh.
- What's that?
- And it'll explode?
Listen, Ken, Colonel Yurulin is the one
who knows his way around here.
We're going to have to enlist his help.
(Tom groans)
- Okay, sir.
- Captain!
- Oh.
- First we must find out--
- [Tom] I'm a little woozy, guys.
- All right.
- Oh, boy.
- [Joe] I have no choice.
- [Tom] I'm feelin' really bad. (chuckles)
- [Rocky] Ken, let's go!
- [Tom] Oh, boy, I feel
like I'm just sinkin' off
a spooky drunk--
(grunts)
(shattering)
- [Joel] Tom! Tom Servo,
what happened, buddy?
- It's all over the seat!
- We gotta get him outta here!
Come on, Crow!
Tom Servo!
(ambulance siren blares)
Oh, my God!
Tom Servo's dead!
He's dying, it must have been that movie!
Oh, man, we're losing him!
- A robot watches a bad film.
It renders him unconscious.
Next on Emergency 911.
- Crow, you gotta snap out
of Shatner and help me!
It means the life of our friend Tom Servo!
- But I must finish TekWars of Venusia,
must direct Star Trek IX,
The Search for Spock's Intelligence,
Hooker's a good cop!
Oh, he's a good, oh--
- Crow, you listen to
me and you listen good!
I need you to snap out of Shatner!
I need you here now!
(sobbing)
Our friend's life hangs
hangs in the balance!
- I'm sorry, Joel, I didn't know!
- I know, man, I know.
But we gotta get our little buddy
out of the bone orchard, okay?
Listen, I need you to run along
and get the defibrillator,
and I'm gonna try to get our brother Tommy
out of the Badlands.
- [Crow] Okay, all right.
- Come on, man.
Come on back, we're all
pullin' for ya, buddy! (sobs)
- [Crow] Hey, Joel, is the defibrillator
the thing that looks like a vacuum cleaner
or a thing that looks
like the battery charger?
- It's a thing that looks
like a battery charger,
now would you get it together,
man, and get out here?
It means Tom Servo's life!
Hang on, buddy!
- All right, all right.
(grunting)
- Okay, hold on, buddy, it's comin'!
Come on home, Tom!
Come on back, buddy!
Clear!
- [Crow] Clear.
(buzzing)
- Nothin'!
- Oh--
- Clear!
- Clear.
(buzzing)
- He's comin' back!
(coughing)
He's comin' back!
- [Crow] Come on, tommy!
(Tom grunting)
- Shaun dancin' up to the plate now.
Beautiful day here at Wrigley Field.
Boy, let me tell ya, perfect
for a nice cold Budweiser.
Ah, and you know Lincoln Carpeting at,
oh! (grunts and coughs)
Joel, Crow!
What the heck happened to me?
- It's okay, buddy, you're
among the living now.
- Oh, that was weird.
I was walking down a long hallway
and at the end of it
there was a bright light,
and a kind man with a beard
reaching his hand out to me,
beckoning me.
And he looked at me as I
got closer and he said,
"Hey, buddy, can ya spare some change?
"I want a cup of coffee." (laughs)
- Oh, everything's a joke to you.
That's great, we got commercial sign.
- We shoulda let you die.
- Ah, life.
(upbeat theme music)
You guys just have no sense of humor.
(Joel and Crow mutter)
You're all spoilsports.
- I have to check the C system over here.
- All right.
- [Joel] Say!
- [Tom] Mmm!
- [Joel] Oh.
(groaning)
- Peeky-boo.
(Tom chuckles)
- [Tom] Okay, let's see here.
Ah, there it is, apartment 3B.
Uh-huh.
(beeping)
- What is this, the super?
- Uh-oh.
- Cheap Japanese crap.
- Yep.
- Look at that.
- [Tom] For cryin' out loud.
You know, you wanna turn the power off
before you work with somethin' like that.
- But he's in a rubber suit.
(Tom sings)
(buzzing)
- [Joel] What? Ohh.
- Captain Joe? Ken here.
- Ken,
I can't hold out much longer.
(Tom grunts)
Hurry up!
(groans)
- [Tom] Whoa, Linda Blair all of a sudden!
- Are you all right?
Captain!
(typing)
- [Tom] Tried to kill me with a forklift.
Ah, cheap Japanese crap, I have to get,
what?
- Yurulin here, what is it?
- Colonel Yurulin,
I'm worried about the
captain, please check on him.
- All right, right away.
- I'm doing it, jeez.
(Tom chuckles)
(grunting)
- [Joel] You know, apparently
it's one of those things
where if the taillight goes
out the whole thing shuts down.
- [Tom] Yeah, pretty much.
- Ooh.
- [Tom] Oh, Jeannie wants
to get out of there, look.
♪ Drink me, drink me ♪
♪ Come on and drink me ♪
- Captain Joe, is anything the matter?
- [Tom] Oh, I'm fine.
Just reflecting on the
Upanishads, young man.
- What's wrong, Captain?
Captain!
(groans)
I'd better take over the controls.
You sit back there!
- [Joel] Yeah, you sleep,
I'll drive till Cleveland.
If it's not one thing it's another
around this crazy ship.
- [Tom] For cryin' out loud.
Hey!
Hey, turn off your brights!
Dim it!
Turn the high beams, the high beams!
- Ken!
We're getting closer!
Get that engine fixed right away!
- Now it's up to Ken.
- Huh?
- [Narrator] The fate of the
entire crew is in his hands.
He will have to locate--
- [Tom] Ayayay.
- [Narrator] Somewhere in the system
before the spacecraft gets
closer to the exploding star.
Otherwise, all is lost.
- That's better.
- I knew votech would pay off.
I'm a graduate of DeVry!
(Crow chuckles)
- [Joel] Mm.
(Tom mutters)
- [Tom] Say.
- [Joel] All right, we
can get free HBO now.
- [Tom] Woo!
- Colonel, I fixed it.
Start the engines, let's get going.
- All right!
- [Tom] Oh, that was
Ken, he's workin' late.
He'll be out for a while, we
might as well go ahead and eat.
This was a really important
part to film here.
- [Joel] Yeah.
Now where I my keys?
I left, oh, they were right, ohhh.
- [Tom] D'oh!
- It isn't working, I can't make it start.
That wasn't it, you better check it again.
- [Ken] But Colonel--
- Don't argue!
- Pump it a few times.
- I don't understand, it's gotta work!
- [Tom] This time I got it.
(Tom whistles)
♪ Sandy Frank, Sandy Frank ♪
♪ Eats a lot of poison shrimp ♪
- (chuckles) Just wrapped a
gum wrapper around the fuse.
- Colonel!
Try it again.
I'm sure it'll work now.
Are you there?
- Now hang up on your end.
- Colonel!
- No, hang up.
I'm hangin' up.
(Tom chuckles)
(adventurous music)
- [Tom] (coughs) I love this song.
- [Joel] What a way to die,
listening to the Tijuana Brass.
(Tom chuckles)
♪ This is the song about
the Bacchus 3 crew ♪
♪ They're gonna die from all the heat ♪
♪ He tried to kill him with a forklift ♪
♪ Ole ♪
(Tom chuckles)
(groaning)
- That looks like a real
uncomfortable Halloween costume.
- [Tom] Mm-hmm.
- [Ken] I've got to keep going!
- [Joel] Got to get date
with girl in hot pants!
(groaning)
(panting)
- [Tom] I know what it is, they're flying
through developer fluid.
(electricity buzzing)
- [Joel] Oh, man, no more Jell-O shots.
I mean it, this is it.
No, I quite today.
- [Tom] There's a drum
major flying the ship now.
- Captain!
We've got the engines working.
Now if we can just get
away from that star!
- Ah, just let me have
my coffee first, okay?
I'm no good without it.
♪ This is the song about
the crew's condition ♪
♪ They all feel like they're gonna puke ♪
♪ He tried to kill me with a forklift ♪
- [Tom] Hoo hoo!
Oh.
What's going on?
- [Crow] Ayayay.
- [Joel] Oh, this is gonna be great.
Speakers on the porch, oh, wow.
- [Ken] That ought to get
the cooling system going.
Just one more connection.
(beeps)
Okay.
- Yeah.
- Good!
- [Tom] Looks good, tastes good, is good!
- [Joel] Good for me.
- [Tom] Good for you.
- [Ken] Can you get her on course?
- He's huge.
- It's no use.
- We're too late now.
- [Tom] It's very hot.
- We've got to go on!
Try again!
- I can't make it.
- Isn't it hot?
- Colonel, can you hear me?
- Colonel?
- [Tom] It's very hot.
Hot in here, it's very hot.
Oh, it's hot in here.
It's hot.
(stammers)
- Oh, no.
We're getting closer to that star.
Looks like I'd better take over. (grunts)
- [Joel] Fine, but towel
off first or something.
- [Tom] Ew.
- [Joel] You're not a kid anymore.
- [Tom] They're having the
film steam cleaned right now
and they need it.
- (grunts) Captain!
I've got it fixed.
It's all working again!
- Great, just in time to see us die.
- I've got it working!
Get going!
- [Joel] Wait, whose
turn is it to pass out?
- [Tom] I'm thinkin' the audience is ready
to pass out about now. (chuckles)
- Ahh!
(Bots yelp)
- [Joel] What, is he
starting the Wild Mouse ride?
(engines boom)
(Tom chuckles)
- Ignition!
- Yes.
- [Ken] We're gonna make it!
Colonel, faster!
Full thrust!
- You want to go faster?
- I'll help ya!
- [Tom] Ooh!
Full thrust! No, no, not you, the engines!
(chuckles)
- [Joel] Kid power!
Red, yellow--
- [Joel And Tom] Black, white!
- We did it!
- Unite!
- We're going!
- We did it, we did it!
We killed 20 minutes of movie!
- Woo!
- Look at that!
- [Ken] I'll take the controls.
- [Joel] I guess you don't
need old Captain Joe anymore.
Hm.
(triumphant music)
- [Tom] Graduates, today
you begin the journey
of the rest of your life.
We may never pass this way again, and, oh.
- (groans) I'm missing graduation.
The music's started, oh no!
(Joel sniffing)
- [Tom] Looks like the tenperature's
coming down. (chuckles)
- See, I'm not even stinky!
- Colonel.
♪ Sandy Frank ♪
(chuckles)
- Thank you.
- Ken?
- Get outta my seat.
- Colonel Yurulin.
You know, both did a terrific job.
I won't forget it.
- This old crate pulled
us through one more time.
(Tom chuckles)
- [Joel] You're cute, both of ya.
- [Ken] Thanks again, Bacchus 3.
- Bacchus! (chuckles)
- Good job!
- [Tom] Now you've done
it again. (chuckles)
- [Joel and Crow] Mighty Jack!
- [Joel] Yeah.
- [Tom] Mighty Jack?
- [Joel] I'm quite a guy, really.
You know?
- [Tom] So?
- Hey, Dan, come on.
- We're goin' fishin'.
- Rise and shine.
- You promised.
- How you doin'?
- [Dan] Still a little groggy.
- [Tammy] Is everybody all right?
- Not too bad.
- I feel great.
Ready for a workout!
- [Joel] Yeah, you got spunk.
I hate spunk.
- What is it?
- [Ken] This is your morning call, sir.
We'll be expecting you all downstairs
in an hour for some tennis.
- [Tom] Is this the Morning Zoo guys?
- Okay, I'll go string my racket.
Say, what happened to room service?
- [Ken] Sorry, sir.
I'm afraid our guests have
to cook their own breakfast.
- [Joel] Enough with the
good-natured ribbing.
Bye!
- You bet!
- [Tom] I love it.
(upbeat theme music)
- [Man] Please hold your
present position for the moment.
We'll be giving you your
landing instructions shortly.
- Shortly?
What's the delay?
- They may have to clear a
landing space for us, that's all.
Message received, we're
holding our position
and waiting to hear from you.
- [Joel] All our best
to Joan and the kids.
(engines power down)
- [Tom] So looks like I'll
just, uh, park there then.
- Oh.
- [Tom] Park in the street, it'll be okay.
- I think I could speed things
up if I had a word with them.
- Oh, Mr. Connections.
- [Tom] Oh, Mr. Sarcasm.
- Colonel Yurulin calling
Saysar Headquarters.
- [Man] Yurulin?
- Yup, we're number one!
- The Earth Space Command
was kind enough to rescue me
from a Karara prison.
I can vouch for every one of the crew.
We'd like to land on Saysar right away.
- [Joel] Bite me?
Is that official?
(radio static crackles)
(worrying music)
- Say, that's the matter down there?
I'm used to having my official requests
dealt with immediately!
- Oh, do you?
- Did you hear that?
- [Man] We read you loud and clear.
- [Joel] We just don't like you.
- [Man] We have no Colonel Yurulin
listed on our officers roster.
- Don't talk nonsense!
Check that roster again!
I've been a senior officer
in the Saysar Command
for the last 20 years!
Captain, I think there's
some sort of a mistake.
- [Tom] Starting with the script.
- Colonel Yurulin, it sounds
like you're pretending
to be someone you aren't.
- Nobody asked you!
This insubordination is unheard of!
- [Joel] Three week's detention for Ken!
- Well, you did reveal a
few vital military secrets
to Karans, didn't ya?
- Wait a second, you're saying
I gave away vital information.
- [Joel] Yeah.
- How did you find out about that?
(Joel and bots gulp)
- By gettin' drunk.
- Anyway, now it seems we're all involved
in this situation together.
- [Tom] Yup.
- This is no trade mission.
You're after that secret
weapon, aren't you?
- Colonel Yurulin--
- Your mouthwash just ain't makin' it.
- If we are after it,
then I think you're the
least likely individual
to lead us to it.
They don't even know you down there.
- It's ridiculous.
Bunch of idiots!
- [Tom] Ship of fools!
- What the heck is goin' on?
(Tom chuckles)
- [Tom] Oh, no, no.
(dramatic music)
Oh, it's starting over!
Help!
- Oh, boy.
- [Tom] I'm gonna bust
it again, let me tell ya.
- Are they really trying to attack?
- [Joel] Is she really going out with him?
- That was just a warning.
Ken, keep your cool.
- You're wrong.
Those guys aren't kidding.
- I can't believe it!
My own people would
never dare shoot at me!
- [Joe] Looks like they have.
Engines full blast!
(booms)
- [Tom] Oh, you know, I just love
the whole incoherent Mighty
Jack quality of this film.
(Tom sings along with music)
(whimpers)
- Could you repeat that please?
- [Tom] It was kind of a kuh-ruh-huh.
- [Joel] I wet 'em.
- [Tom] This week, join Jonny, Hadgi,
Race Bannon and Bandit. (barks)
Jonny Quest.
- We're surrounded!
They'll attack again any minute!
(Tom sings along with music)
- Don't let insects
spoil your garden party.
- Captain!
- [Joel] Pia Zadora?
No, aw.
- Ugh.
- [Tom] Oh no, they're being
attacked by Norelco razors!
- Even the name says merry Christmas.
- [Tom] It, uh (sighs)--
- (grunts) I'm going to get them!
- [Joel] It's too dark
to go out on your bike!
- [Tom] Get back here.
- Don't fire back, try to make contact!
Tell them it's a mistake!
- What are you, Captain
Kirk all of a sudden?
(Tom chuckles)
- Mistake? This is for real.
Get ready to counter attack.
- Yes, sir!
- [Joel] Magic booze bottle, take me away!
(Tom sings along with music)
- [Tom] Ole!
(lasers zap)
(Tom chuckles)
Ooh.
- I got it! (chuckling)
- Oh, is killing fun, Ken?
Does it amuse you?
♪ Let's all watch Ken ♪
♪ As he tries to kill the badguys ♪
♪ They'll taste their steel ♪
♪ Then they'll drink their own blood ♪
♪ They'll try to kill
him with a forklift ♪
- [Tom] I'm makin' this up as I go.
- [Joel] Faster, pussy-Ken, kill, kill.
- All right, go.
- [Tom] Like you've never goed before.
- I'll show 'em.
- I'll run away!
Then they'll be sorry they picked on me.
(mimics childish sobbing)
(lasers zap)
Why is Ken behaving like this?
- [Tom] Because it's bitter
and because it's his heart.
- [Joel] Bang, bang!
Killing is fun!
(lasers zap)
(explosion booms)
- Ho, and he picks up the spare!
- [Tom] Yeah, so let's
review the plot so far.
They went into outer space, and, uh,
let's see, uh, oh, wait a minute,
it's, uh--
- Yeah.
- [Tom] They went into space and,
it's on the tip of my tongue.
- Oh, I know, I know, they,
uh, suffocated for a while--
- Yeah, yeah.
- And, uh--
- [Joel] And then I think
came lots of explosions?
- [Tom] I think a bang,
zoom. (mimics explosions)
- [Joel] I think that's it.
- [Tom] That's stuff.
- Whew! I really enjoyed that.
- You're sick, buddy.
- Don't get so enthusiastic.
- Now that they know where we are,
they're gonna send out the next wave.
- Well, you know the old
saying, an eye for an eye.
- Breakfast and tennis! (chuckles)
- Captain, here they come again!
- [Tom] Ooh!
Catch 'em if you can.
♪ Ooh ♪
- There's no way out of this, sir.
Sooner or later, one of
them is gonna score a hit.
- Off the bong.
- Colonel Yurulin!
- Woo!
- [Joe] Can you guide us to a safe place
to make an emergency landing?
- Uh, my uncle's got a
planet, let's crash there.
- Look, if you wanna stay alive,
you're gonna have to help us.
Where can we land?
- Well, I do know of a place.
- All right.
Tell us where it is.
- Everyone calls it the Devil's Desert.
- [Joel] Sounds pretty neat!
- If you're really
willing to take the risk,
I'll be glad to guide you.
- Okay.
Let's go!
- We're goin' to Vegas, everybody!
(cheering)
(engines boom)
- [Joel] Looks like the big, blue marble.
- Sure does.
- Mm-hmm.
- [Tom] Okay, let's see here.
There's Satan's Triangle,
Lucifer's Elbow, uh, oh,
there, Devil's Desert.
- Flying over teenage skin eruptions, sir.
- [Tom] Ew.
(Tom laughs)
- Huh?
- We're landing there?
- You got a problem with that?
(Tom sings along with music)
- [Tom] Nice effect, though.
- Hold on tight!
This is going to be a rough one.
- [Tom] We'd better learn to get along.
- In the pipe, five by five.
(Tom chuckles)
- Careful, careful!
These sands are treacherous!
- They're headed straight for the dock!
(grunting)
(slamming)
(rumbling)
- [Joel] You know, this film
looks like it's scrapin' the bottom.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Well, should I let her down?
- Ah, note to myself.
Put landing gear on this baby.
(rumbling)
- [Tom] Ahh.
Arrakis, Dune, desert planet.
- Damn, I just washed this thing.
- [Joel] Looks like one of my old
ski club overnights, you know?
- [Tom] Ooh, Alpine Valley.
- [Joel] Yup.
- A planet that evolved from carob?
I don't think so.
♪ In-A-Gadda-Da-Vida, baby ♪
(groaning)
(uncertain music)
- [Ken] Tammy.
Tammy!
- [Tom] Tell me true.
- A girl?
A Grimald warrior's supposed to be brave!
- Yes.
- Get up.
Sir!
(Tom mimics snoring)
(Joel babbles)
- [Joel] Football practice!
- [Tom] Uh, what, what,
who turned off the TV set?
- Bloody Marys all around.
- (grunts) Come on,
pull yourself together.
- [Tom] Are they telling him
to pull yourself together?
- Ken, better check the others.
- Okay.
- Oh, yeah, aye-aye, captain.
- Dan! Snap out of it!
(Tom mimics snoring)
- Billy!
- Don't be a hero!
- [Ken] Colonel Yurulin!
- Ah, drive through clowns!
I want Sunrise Biscuit, come outta there!
- [Joe] Ah, will you look at that?
So hot in here it feels like a steam bath.
- [Joel] And me without a towel.
- Rocky, better get
the area on the screen.
- Okay.
- [Tom] Oh wow, they gotta
watch their own reruns?
What a nightmare.
- [Rocky] I wonder how
much damage we've got.
- I don't know.
I want every inch of
this craft checked out.
- Every inch.
- Yes, sir!
- Even the inch under your seat?
- Every inch, get to it.
- Every inch?
- Even the dirtiest inch in the kitchen?
- [Tom] Every single inch.
- [Crow] Even that inch that's--
- At least we're on the ground again.
- [Joel] Seems like there's
an inch over there that they--
- All right, I better go help the others.
(upbeat theme music)
- New from the Star Force
line of action figures,
it's Captain Joe, the boozy, brawling,
bloated Bacchus 3 commander
from the beloved Fugitive Alien series!
- Dizzy Gillespie cheeks sold separately.
- Yes, he swaggers, he
staggers, and he even talks.
- Uh, a fellow would do a lot worse
than touring with the lot of Bacchus 3.
Set 'em up, barkeep.
- Flask and travel bar not included.
- Yes, with your Captain Joe action figure
you'll be in a constant
state of excitement
while he's in a state of denial.
- Uh, I only drink on the weekend.
I can drink!
- Existential void where prohibited.
- Sure, he's got a problem,
but you don't have to
watch him deteriorate.
After all, you spent 9.95 for him!
- Tax and license not included!
- You can have hours
of fun as you organize
a crisis intervention for Captain Joe.
- [Joel] Captain Joe,
I am not gonna sit here
and watch you deteriorate.
Captain Joe, when Ken and
I had you over to eat,
you got drunk on cooking sherry,
and made a pass at me,
and threw up all over
the Malibu Dream House.
Captain Joe, dude, I loved you,
but I'm not gonna sit here
and watch you cowa-bungle your life.
- And don't forget, kids,
if Captain Joe refuses to deal
with the issues, you can always--
♪ Try to kill him with a forklift ♪
- 12 step workbook optional!
Product not included in some boxes.
Joe Namath netted slingshot
briefs sold separately.
(alarm buzzing)
- We got movie sign!
(shouting)
(dramatic, urgent music)
- Well, let's go.
(whistling)
- [Tom] Hey!
- Hey, where you goin'?
- [Joel] I'm sorry.
- [Tom] Thanks.
- You and Tammy are staying here.
- What for?
- As soon as we've left,
I want you bring Bacchus
3 to a safer place.
- Sir, do you think you're
doing the right thing?
- What do you mean?
- I was told when the
mission is dangerous, uh,
it's the older men who are
the ones to stay behind.
- [Joe] Rocky, that's an order.
- [Joel] Impressive eye contact.
- Sir, that's crazy!
You can't go on a forced march
through this desert at your age.
Let me go!
- I'll command my own mission.
- You--
- Pull my finger.
- Do as you're told.
I'll never shirk my responsibilities.
- Not even when my hip cracks.
(grave music)
- [Tom] Say.
(gun cocks)
- Rocky!
- Again?
- This is one order I can't obey.
- Disobey it over my dead body.
- Okay.
- Rocky, don't!
- Shoot me if you've got the guts.
My orders still stand!
- [Tom] Squeeze.
(gun fires)
(gasping)
- Hey.
(groaning)
He did it.
- [Tammy] Captain!
- [Tom] Oh, Captain, my captain!
- (grunts) I'll kill you for that!
- Don't get excited.
I wouldn't shoot my chief
with live ammunition.
It's a knockout dart.
- Of course, it pierced his colon.
- It'll just put him out of
commission for an hour or so.
Help me get him to some place comfortable.
Ken, grab his legs.
Now then, we've got a
mission to accomplish.
- [Tom] That is gonna be the
first time he's passed out cold
and he's gonna wake up sober! (chuckles)
- Peek-a-boo.
- [Joel] It's Abbott and
Costello in Turning Japanese.
(Tom sings riff from "Turning Japanese")
- All right, let's go.
(adventurous music)
- [Tom] And man was born of woman,
and they both inhabited the earth.
- Tammy, I want you to contact us
as soon as you've moved
Bacchus 3 to a safer place.
Call us on our micro-radios.
- Right.
- We'll try to maintain
contact from our end.
And don't forget, keep us in radar range.
- You can count one it.
- Oh, and, uh, you better
lock up the liquor cabinet
and hide the key, if you know what I mean.
♪ We're headed for adventure ♪
♪ We'll leave Tammy behind ♪
♪ We're gonna pad out the film some more ♪
♪ And you'll fall asleep ♪
♪ Three, four ♪
♪ We're climbing the sandy hill ♪
♪ Like you really care ♪
- That's good.
- [Joel] That's plenty.
- [Tom] Sorry.
- Faster!
- [Crew] Yes, sir.
- There's spiders all over me!
Get 'em off me, get 'em off me! (sobs)
- [Joel] You know, it's
the funniest sensation.
The room's not spinning.
Hm.
- Hm.
- I'll kill that Rocky.
- Again?
(Tom chuckles)
- [Tom] Hit him.
- [Joel] I took the liberty of
changing your jumpsuit, sir.
- Are they in radar range?
(beeping)
- Yes, sir.
They're right here on the screen.
22 degrees east-northeast.
(clicks)
(beeping)
- [Joel] I'm not in right now,
but if you'd like to leave
a message with my shoulder--
- Rocky, read me?
- Again?
(Tom chuckles)
- [Joel] Stop it.
- Rocky!
- Again?
- [Joel] Stop it!
- We're advancing on our objective.
- That was a dirty trick
you played on me. (grunts)
- [Rocky] Why don't you court martial me
over a cold beer when
this mission is over?
- [Tom] And a shot?
- All right.
I want you guys to be careful.
This is a very tricky operation.
- Yes, sir, and you get a good rest.
One of these days you'll
thank me for what I did.
- [Joel] Shoulder phone off.
- Rocky.
- Again?
- Sorry.
(radar beeping)
(determined music)
- [Tom] Pong?
Hmm.
- That Rocky.
- Again?
- I'll bust him when this is over.
(Joel grunts)
(Tammy giggles)
- [Joel] Sorry, I was thinking
about something else, sir.
(Tom sings along with score)
♪ We are marching on a big sand hill ♪
♪ We realize you've had your fill ♪
♪ As we march upon this big sand hill ♪
- [Joel] Just stop it.
- Hey, corn.
Hey, corn?
- Get down!
There's a watchtower.
- [Tom] Oh, but I kid
gentleman's witnesses,
ladies and gentlemen. (chuckles)
I love them.
(Crow chuckles)
(snare drumming)
- [Joel] Hey, check it out,
they're fighting ZZ Top!
- Oh.
(dramatic sting music)
- [Tom] Huh?
- Hey, Dave.
Oh, hiya, Evan.
- [Tom] I think they swiped this music
from Mission Impossible.
(Tom sings along with score)
- Get in as close as you can.
I'll try to divert the guards.
- And watch out for the percussionists.
They might have tambourines.
- [Tom] Let go of my leg.
- What's the matter, don't you trust me?
- What guarantee do we have
that you won't double cross us?
- [Joel] Oh, I'll leave you my keys.
- Look, if you attack that post head on,
those machine guns'll mow you down
in a matter of seconds.
- Hey, Moe!
- You know the way I feel.
I've got a score to
settle with this country.
- [Tom] And a song in my heart.
- [Joel] He's true to his school.
- Okay, I'll still keep you covered.
- Shh! Now.
- Shh.
(dramatic, foreboding music)
- Walk the way I walk.
All hunkered down like that.
- [Joel] Plan B, Merce Cunningham!
(subtle, sneaky music)
(Tom speaks in foreign language)
- [Joel] Hey, it's high definition TV.
- [Tom] Neat.
(Crow speaks in foreign language)
Oh, hey, you got a little
toilet paper on your shoe there.
(chuckles)
He's comin' out of the loo.
- Hi-keeba.
Now, on with the--
(Tom mutters)
- [Rocky] He did sell us out!
(alarm blares)
- [Joel] Uh, sir, it's
the Peter Frampton alarm!
Only goes off in the 70s.
- I should have known it.
- [Ken] A rat always returns to his hole.
(menacing music)
(alarm blares)
(Tom mimics alarm)
- [Tom] This is Operation
Desert Bore. (chuckles)
- [Joel] Sounds like the teacher
from the Peanuts TV specials.
(gun cocks)
- He's going to shoot us himself!
- Well, I'm flattered!
- Attack!
(shouting)
(machine gun fires)
- [Joel] Oh, no!
(screaming)
- Gallipoli.
- [Tom] Oh, neat.
(machine gun fires)
(screaming)
- [Joel] Cross of Iron, in color.
- [Tom] Ohh.
George!
Paul!
John!
Pete Best!
- You like my fort?
Made it out of refrigerator boxes!
- Come on out!
- Hooray!
- [Joel] Now it looks
like Lawrence of Arabia
except for the pink, shiny pleather suits.
(Tom chuckles)
(upbeat music)
- Ah, come on, girls!
(laughing)
- [Tom] (chuckles)
We're filled with mirth!
Mirth Cunningham!
- [Joel] Hey, where have
all the dead guys gone?
- [Tom] Aww.
- [Yurulin] Looks like I
had you worried for a while.
- You think anything's wrong?
- It seems all right so far, sir.
- Good.
- Hey, that Westinghouse symbol
kinda got wrecked in the crash.
(Tom chuckles)
- Tammy?
- [Tammy] Yes, sir.
- We've gotta get this ship out of here
before the next sandstorm.
That clear?
- (chuckles) Yes, sir.
- [Joel] Okay, now
here's the liquor store,
and there's Tom Thumb.
Now you take two lefts, and you're there.
No problem.
- This is it.
- [Yurulin] The red
star is a security zone.
- [Tom] (mimics radio
static) We are still 35 miles
to weather ship Tango Delta.
(triumphant music)
- Okay, now it's our turn to move.
Let's go!
- Hi-keeba, Captain.
(Tom sings along with score)
♪ Now strap in tight ♪
♪ Let's get set for action ♪
♪ To launch the ship out of the sand ♪
♪ He tried to kill us with a forklift ♪
- Huzzah! (chuckles)
I love that.
- [Narrator] While Captain
Joe moves the spacecraft
closer to the secret installation,
the crew of Bacchus 3,
disguised as Saysar soldiers,
advances cautiously.
- [Joel] Me? I'm Carl, the narrator.
I used to work with Ken.
I do these voiceovers to finance
what I really want to do.
- [Tom] And what's that, Carl?
- [Joel] Decoupage.
- [Tom] (laughs) Thank you.
- What are they doing at the
Joshua Tree National Forest?
- [Tom] You got me.
(beeping)
- [Joel] Oh, now this is the nice side
of the Devil's Desert.
- [Tom] Oh, of course.
- [Rocky] Have they got the super weapon
stored in this depot?
- No, but they've got Mr. Freezies.
- [Yurulin] It must be here.
- [Ken] It sure doesn't look
like a high security installation.
- Yeah, looks like nothing.
- Yeah.
- Guess most of it's underground.
- [Tom] Yeah, they even got a
bowling alley in the basement.
It's just like the White
House, it's really cool.
- [Joel] It's a nature outing.
- [Tom] Oh, how charming.
- Stop here.
- Wait, there's your punch!
- [Joel] Damn, zither balls everywhere!
- Oh, no!
- [Tom] Okay.
Ahh.
- [Yurulin] Don't go near that!
- [Tom] Looks like we're
in the Giraffe Lot here.
Hm?
- [Joel] Hm, he's makin' somethin'.
(grunting)
(electricity crackles)
- [Tom] Ooh!
- Oh.
- Hi-keeba.
- Well.
Good thing we're not branches.
- It's just as I thought.
They've got the whole installation
surrounded by a lethal ray.
- Martha Raye.
- Wow.
- That's all we need.
- This super weapon must be
an incredibly powerful device
if they need this elaborate
a system to protect it.
- No, Ken, don't try it.
- [Joel] Yeah, nice canky
you're workin' on there, Rocky.
- [Yurulin] It'll vaporize you in seconds.
(grunting)
(Joel and bots grunt)
- Huh?
- How?
- The Fosbury flop!
- [Joel] They've discovered Flubber!
Hoo hoo!
What fun! (chuckles)
- [Tom] Woo-hoo-hoo-hoo.
- [Ken] Okay, Billy,
you're next. Let's go.
- What about my rifle?
- Watch!
- There you are!
- There's your rifle!
(Joel and bots babble)
- That red spot hasn't moved an inch.
- But it's healing nicely.
- I hope they're all right.
- (chuckles) They'll be fine.
They know if they blow this one,
I'm gonna kick them
right out of the service.
- You remind me of my father.
- [Joel] Oh, let's keep
our mind on our (coughs)
work, shall we?
Hoo hoo, it's fun!
You're my friend!
(Tom babbles)
- [Rocky] Having a Star Wolf
along has its advantages.
- Rocky, let's go.
- I'm with you.
- [Tom] And without you. (chuckles)
♪ Sandy Frank ♪
(Tom sings)
Oh, wait, musical.
- [Joel] All boring on the western front.
(Tom chuckles)
- I'll say.
- Rocky?
- Come over here.
- Again?
- [Tom] Oh, he did it again.
- I'm way over here.
- Look, check that out
with your field classes.
(babbling and cross-talking)
- Hm.
- Say, not half bad!
- So it is underground.
- Rocky!
♪ There's a world going on ♪
♪ Underground ♪
(Tom sings)
- It's us!
Hey, wait a minute, did we
just do another hop thing?
- [Joel] Hey, it's us again.
Are we unstuck in time or something?
- [Rocky] It won't be easy
getting into this place.
- How will we do it?
- Easy.
- Wait a minute.
- Those ID tags.
If we can get our hands on them,
we can waltz right through.
- Why not take the whole uniform?
- [Tom] And rumba right in.
- I'm Chet, welcome to
Arby's training school.
Again, I'm Chet if you need anything.
I'll write it down.
(goofy music)
- [Joel] Are you seein' what I'm seein'?
They're nude!
- Oh-hoo!
- Good luck.
- [Tom] Artie Johnson, I thought so!
(Crow sings along with score)
- Jack Sue.
- [Tom] Hey.
Boots are made for walkin'.
(Tom sings along with score)
♪ Lay down a boogie ♪
♪ And play that funky music till you die ♪
(struggling)
- Jack Oakie?
- Pass.
- [Tom] Huh?
- Oh, that was easy.
Again, I'm Chet.
- [Guard] Haven't seen
those guys here before.
- [Joel] Nice lookin' guys, though.
- You know how it is,
they're always sending in reinforcements.
- [Tom] We are 22 minutes
to weather ship Tango Delta.
- Captain!
- I saw it.
- They made it inside.
I knew they would.
- [Tom] Oh.
(hesitant music)
(Tom sings along)
Hmm.
- He got the coal mine, I got the shaft.
(Tom chuckles)
- [Joel] It's Bruce Lee, and Bruce Lee
in a collision course with wackiness!
(Tom chuckles)
- Crotch cam, I'm huge!
(Tom sings along with score)
- [Joel] Hey, do you
guys have a hall pass?
Come on.
- Hi-keeba, get that suit pressed.
And trim the hair in our nose.
That's all.
(sudden, dramatic music)
- [Tom] Zither lamps everywhere!
Huzzah.
(panting)
Nice boots.
- [Joel] Over here, a little
further, behind this rock.
Yeah, mm-hmm.
- For the walking sequence,
special director Roger Corman.
- [Tom] Quit panting, shut up!
(Crow whistles)
- [Joel] Nothing, nothing.
Act natural, hi!
(bots hum casually)
- Now!
- [Tom] Garrison's Gorillas, in color!
(hesitant music)
(Tom sings with score)
- [Soldiers] Saysar!
- Romero!
- [Tom] Did somebody say
Cesar Romero? (chuckles)
- Okay, let's do it now.
- [Tom] What, here?
Here?
- Right now.
- Hold it.
(Tom sings along with score)
Now!
(grunting)
- [Joel] It's mom's old Vaudeville stuff!
- [Tom] What do ya know?
Wait a minute, it's the
lobby at Caesar's Palace!
I thought so.
- Cool.
(menacing music)
- [Tom] Are they blue or not?
- [Joel] The plastic thing!
- [Tom] Ooh!
- I can smash this alone.
Is that all their is to it?
- Quiet! Just wait.
Your superhuman strength may not be enough
against a machine like that.
We've gotta do this slowly and carefully.
- So you can thoroughly bore the viewers.
- [Tom] Mm-hmm.
- Whoa.
- Neat.
- [Tom] Guys, I'm having
a hard time telling
how big this things is.
Can we have something on the screen
to figure out the scale here?
- [Announcer] Attention, attention.
This is Field Marshall Telsa,
your commander-in-chief.
- And Grand Poobah!
- [Tesla] I am proud to
announce that a new age
has begun for the people of Saysar.
- [Joel] Oh, that explains the crystals.
- Ohh.
- [Tom] New age and all.
- [Tesla] We can meet any challenge.
Not even the supposedly
invincible Wolf Raiders
from Valna star can threaten us anymore.
From now on, we shall be able to--
- [Tom] Oh! Sorry, ladies.
- [Tesla] And destroy their very planet.
- [Tom] Lunch today is chicken-fried stake
and whipped potatoes.
- Are ready to dominate world!
Sir, we've achieved
the final breakthrough!
We're getting ready to--
- No speeches, solider!
Get back to your post.
- Please excuse me, sir.
- I promise to pay more
attention to my duties.
- [Joel] What a dope, hit him!
Come on.
- Halt! Nobody's allowed past this point.
- You must be a new recruit.
- No, sir, a blue recruit!
- Go on in.
- Yes, sir, right away.
- Out of the way.
- [New Recruit] Sir, I
was ordered not to let
anyone past this point.
- These men are all right.
- [Joel] They're really good
guys, especially that Chopper.
He's a nut.
- [Tom] All done in there?
- It's a Super Tom Servo
with thrush-busters and glass packs!
Wow!
- [Tom] Tunnel rim, four barrel!
- Chopped and channeled.
- [Tom] Cool.
- Look at that!
- Like a beating heart!
- [Tom] Like a beating heart
liberal! (chuckles and coughs)
- Ken, you plant the time bomb.
- Okay.
(subtle, sneaky music)
- Wait, they're gonna destroy it
with refrigerator magnets?
- Yes, my detachment was on maneuvers
in the northernmost part of the country.
- [Joel] Yeah, it was a
blast, it was really fun.
- [Tom] You're a sleek, young fellow.
Thin, trim.
- It's an honor to serve here.
- Yes, sir, I know that sir.
We had a competition in our unit.
- I was the bluest.
- I was the winner.
- That's why I was selected for guard duty
at this installation.
- [Joel] Ah, you've created
quite a little world for yourself, I see.
(Tom chuckles)
- Hide the bomb.
It's Yurulin with that kid.
- [Yurulin] Open the door!
I haven't got all day!
- [Tom] Well, I do,
but I don't wanna give it all
up for this is what I mean.
- Everything all right?
- [Ken] Yes sir, everything's just fine.
- Good, let's go.
- [Tom] Bye, thanks for the check up.
He's so cool.
(door closes)
Thanks.
- You're a fine soldier!
The next time I see your commander,
I'll tell him you're doing a good job.
- Oh, thank you, Colonel.
- Let's do lunch.
You're it.
- [Joel] I could talk to that guy
till I'm blue in the face.
(Tom hums)
- Thanks for keeping him distracted.
The time bombs are ready to go off.
- [Tom] Oh, he's a swell
kid, hate to see him die.
(upbeat theme music)
- They're playing my song!
(orchestrated music)
- [Tom] Kirk Listing number 15,
Eine kleine Nachtmusik.
- [Joel] Masterpiece
Theater is brought to you
by a grant from the Mobil Corporation.
- You can't just stand there, sir.
- Watch me.
- We've got to get out of here.
- This is our Saysar anthem.
- So what?
- Every day at this hour,
we all stand at attention
and renew our loyalty to the homeland.
- That's great.
While the others are standing
at attention, we'll get out.
- Yeah, that's great,
you stand at attention,
and I'll pick you up and carry ya.
Come on!
- [Joel] Hey, are those
Blaupunkt speakers?
They sound great.
♪ And the home of the brave ♪
(Tom hocks and spits)
- Hey, buddy.
- What's wrong?
- Can he hear?
Colonel!
- Psst!
- [Joel] Exnay on the edgeplay!
- It's that music.
It has an effect on him.
When he hears it, he snaps to attention.
- The guy's crazy!
We've got no time for patriotism now.
That bomb is about to go off.
Colonel, we gotta get out of here!
Come on down, sir,
there's no time to lose!
- [Tom] Huh?
- My country needs me!
- Colonel!
- You know, his country
would win more wars
if its national anthem was shorter.
- What happened to you?
- [Joel] Somebody finger-painted me!
- Spy attack.
- [Tom] Get off my chest.
- [Soldier] Red alert! Red alert!
- Message received, nobody gets in here.
- Without a tuxedo and
a note from Mr. Gotti!
- You can't go in there!
- Out of my way!
- [Tom] Infidel.
- Stay where you are!
One more step and I'll shoot!
(gun fires)
- [Joel] He didn't take a step.
What is he, a Chicago cop, that guy?
- [Tom] Oh look, he's doing Joe Cocker.
♪ What would you think ♪
- Harvey's lost one good worker.
He was the best damn fry cook they had.
(tuts)
- [Tom] Adios, sweet friend.
- [Joel] Space Camp with Kate Capshaw.
- [Tom] We are unable to
reach the primary target, sir.
We will go to alternate target at Laputa.
- It's 15 minutes.
- We're not famous anymore.
- Ken and the others aren't out.
There's something wrong, sir.
- I have confidence in them.
They're all professionals.
- [Joel] Yeah, I'll be inside
a bottle if you need me.
- [Tom] I hate patronizing answers.
(zapping)
(yelps)
- [Tom] Hm. Ooh.
(yelping)
- Our prisoners are baked, not fried.
- [Billy] Dan!
Dan!
- Billy!
- [Tom] Do not attempt to adjust your TV.
- Don't wait for me, go on ahead.
(gun fires)
- [Tom] Oh, wait, shootin' the wrong guy.
- Billy, save yourself!
- [Enemy] There they are!
- [Joel] Laser wall by Peter Max.
(guns fire)
(Tom sings along with score)
- [Dan] Billy, don't
try to fight them off!
Run for it!
- I'll come back for you, Dan!
- Yeah right, you'll never see him again.
- [Joel] Hey, this is great.
He looks like a canceled stamp.
(Crow chuckles)
(Tom sings along with score)
- Well, time for a drink. Yep.
- It's getting later and later.
Tammy? I think we'd better take off.
Ready?
- Yes, Captain!
- [Tom] Right.
- Flyin' high now.
You're into what?
- What?
Dan was trapped?
- Yes, I tried to help him, but--
- [Joel] He already
chewed half his leg off!
- [Tom] Ew.
- I heard what he said.
I can rescue Dan.
- Can you get him out
before the bomb goes off?
- I can try.
- We've gotta be sure.
- We'll never save Dan
by talking about it!
- [Tom] Well, then let's sing about it!
- Billy, you stop worrying.
(Tob sobs)
Okay.
- Thanks for cheering me up.
You're a pip!
- You guys better get outta here, quick.
- Nothin' doin'.
(grunts) I'm going with you.
- No, you're not!
You get back to the ship.
- I want to help you rescue Dan.
- [Joel] I want to know what love is.
- Your injured leg,
you'd only be in my way.
(pained grunting)
(device buzzing)
- This is great. Do we have to see this?
Come on.
- [Joel] Sounds like he's getting a tattoo
with the Bizzy Buzz Buzz or something.
- [Tom] Oh, Victor Kiam,
why did you have to buy the company?
- What is the nature of your mission here?
Huh?
(pained screaming)
- [Joel] Shaves like a blade! (grunts)
- [Tom] Or your money back.
- I'm going to have to drill again.
- You were collecting
information on our secret weapon.
You're a spy, aren't you?
Huh?
- [Tom] Now rinse, please.
Is it safe?
(device buzzing)
- Who sent you here?
- If you don't look
good, we don't look good.
(pained grunting)
See, you're not enjoying this.
Now I think you'd better answer us.
Otherwise, things will get even worse.
Huh?
- [Joel] Just a little
off the top! (grunts)
- [Interrogator] Talk! Talk!
- [Tom] Talk Talk by Talk Talk
from the album Talk Talk.
(engines boom)
Yup.
Fella could get rich flyin' a crop duster
if he lived long enough. (chuckles)
I don't think that was the best.
- [Joel] Man, should I be driving?
I mean, I've already got two DWIs.
(dramatic music)
(Crow chirps)
(gun fires)
- [Tom] Ooh.
(pained grunting)
- Oh! (chuckles)
Interpretive death.
Flip shot to a summersault!
Pretty routine, I've seen that before.
(grunting)
- [Joel] Hey, it's a three legged race!
- Or five.
- [Tom] Huh?
(beeping)
Oh, snaggletooth!
- [Tammy] Captain, they're
back on the screen!
- That's great.
(bots growl)
Didn't I tell you that
they were professionals?
- Yes, sir.
(men grunting)
- [Joel] Professional what?
- Is this dubbed?
It sounds like it might be dubbed.
- Pretty much I think.
- It's dubbed.
- Hey, time's running out! Hurry!
- There's only seven minutes left.
- I know that, you idiot!
- Dan's still in there!
- [Joel] And he's got
the keys to your van,
and his dad was gonna buy us a keg!
- [Tom] Here, you want a sandwich?
I got chicken salad and some
peanut butter and jelly.
- I didn't mean to yell at you.
- Rocky, it's all my fault.
I should never have abandoned him.
- It's no one's fault.
And if anyone can save him, it's Ken.
You did the right thing in getting help.
- Yeah, it's Ken's fault!
- Yeah.
- Now pull yourself together.
- Look at that!
(whooshing)
Over there!
- [Tom] Odd, that plane's dusting crops
where there ain't no crops!
- Just in time!
- Cool.
- [Interrogator] This is
your last chance, Earthling.
Now, who sent you here and why?
- [Joel] Now remember, the first blade
pulls the whisker out, capisce?
(pained grunting)
(buzzing)
- Weapon. (grunting)
- [Tom] What?
- [Torturer] Now we're getting somewhere.
Who sent you?
(pained grunting)
- [Tom] Oil can?
Did he say oil can?
- Increase the voltage!
How much do you think you can take?
- He's an electro-holic.
Ohm is too many and a
trillion isn't enough.
(Tom chuckles)
- [Tom] Ohm is the loneliest
number, you know. (chuckles)
- He fainted.
Hurry! All of you!
We've got to locate that bomb!
- Yes, sir. Come on, men!
- Yes, sir!
- Oh, no, you don't!
Dan!
- Hm?
- [Tom] Van Damme and Van Damme
in Van Damme You All to Hell. (laughs)
Woo!
- Double dog Van Damme.
(grunting)
Oh, this is great, the director chooses
closeups for the action sequences.
- [Tom] (chuckles) Perfect.
- [Joel] Oh, great, they're still parking.
- [Tom] Boy.
- Hard to find a spot.
(wheezing)
- [Tom] They communicate by gasping.
(Tom mimics gasping)
- [Joel] Hey, look, Edelweiss.
- Pretty.
- Rocky, hurry!
- Again?
- Where's Ken and Dan?
- [Tom] That's a good
question, let's talk about it
on the way home.
- In five minutes, that bomb goes off.
And they're still in there.
We have to leave.
- Why are they still in there?
What's happened to Ken?
- [Joel] Ah, he's into Barbie.
It's sad, really.
- [Tom] But you're skirting
the whole Ken issue.
(worrying music)
- Every time I really like a guy.
(lasers fire)
(grunting)
- [Joel] You know, I love my work.
I never think I gotta go
to work, I just love it.
- [Tom] Oh.
(grunting)
Hi-keeba?
Hey!
Hi-keeba.
Nice dismount.
Gymkata!
Ho, hey, ho!
(shouting)
Gymkata! Hai!
Ah, it's fun.
(grunting and shouting)
- Hm.
- Say.
- [Tom] Good one.
- [Ken] Huh-shick!
- [Tom] What did, Ken!
- Easy, that's it!
- [Tom] Easy does it.
- [Joel] I'm serious about mufflers.
(Tom chuckles)
- Three minutes till the explosion.
- I can get in a quick one.
- [Tom] Yeah, we gotta get
in a quick one, too, guys.
- Please, wait, sir.
Ken and Dan can't be that far away.
(worrying music)
(panting)
Ken!
Ken made it!
- [Tom] All right, I'm
feelin' really good!
- Yeah.
- Oh, boy!
♪ This is the song
starting off our medley ♪
♪ Our favorite Fugitive Alien songs ♪
♪ Don't try to kill us with a forklift ♪
♪ It won't take very long ♪
♪ Relax and sing along ♪
- Thank you, thank you.
- You know, Tommy, a
movie like Fugitive Alien
can make you cry,
and it can make you cry.
- Ah me, yes.
- But the thing I treasure most,
and I'm speaking from the heart here,
this is totally off script--
- Mm-hmm.
- Is the music.
- Oh, this is so true, mon Crow.
Songs of love an adventure,
and if I may, whimsy, no? (chuckles)
But you know, my favorite
was the heartrending ballad
in which the wistful Tammy
pledges her love to Ken.
- It goes a little something like this.
(clears throat)
- Two, three, four.
♪ I love Ken, he is my sweet friend ♪
♪ And I love him ♪
♪ I love Ken ♪
♪ He is my sweet friend ♪
♪ And I love him ♪
♪ I'm so blue ♪
♪ 'Cause I don't think Ken loves me ♪
♪ 'cause I don't think Ken loves me ♪
♪ I'm all messed up inside ♪
♪ I might have to off him ♪
♪ I'll frame Rocky ♪
♪ And get away Scott free ♪
♪ I'll frame Rocky and
get away Scott free ♪
♪ I love Ken, he is my sweet
friend, and I love him ♪
(Tom sings in foreign language)
♪ I'm so blue 'cause I
don't think Ken loves me ♪
♪ I'm all missed up inside ♪
♪ I might have to off him ♪
♪ I saw three ships come sailing in ♪
♪ On Christmas day, on Christmas day ♪
♪ I'll frame Rocky and
get away Scott free ♪
♪ I love Ken, I love Ken ♪
- All right, this band is marvelous!
Aren't they ladies and gentlemen?
Cambot Brown and his band renown!
Give it up for 'em!
(upbeat jazzy music)
- Yeah!
- Smokin'.
- One, two, three.
♪ It's got a real cool feel ♪
(Tom scats)
♪ Flying high with Star Wolf ♪
- Hah!
♪ We're firin' up the ship ♪
♪ And we're hittin' the town ♪
- Boogie, boogie!
♪ With groovy Ken and Tammy ♪
- Yeah! Hah!
♪ Swingin' Rocky and Joe ♪
♪ And there's two other guys
who we don't really know ♪
♪ Forget 'em, lay down the boogie ♪
♪ And head for the stars, man ♪
- Thanks, Joel.
Oh, that was fun.
But if I can get a little
serous for a moment,
well, I was wondering where we'd be
without our boys and girls
in shiny red pleather.
It makes me proud to know that
they're out there somewhere.
♪ Look and you see, flying so fancy free ♪
♪ Fighting for you and me ♪
♪ Captain Joe and the gang ♪
♪ When they pass by ♪
♪ Feel it in pumpkin pie ♪
♪ Tenth in the neck would die ♪
- Tempo.
♪ Return the blue ♪
- That's really good, Gypsy.
- Do you wanna do one with me?
- Huh?
- Oh, what?
- Let's all do it.
- Okay.
♪ We're are gonna find Sandy Frank ♪
♪ We just wanna him why ♪
♪ We wanna stick it to Sandy Frank ♪
♪ And sit on his chest
and gob on his face ♪
♪ And make him cry ♪
- Yeah!
- That's right, take it home!
- I'm feelin' really good!
- Feels so good it shows!
- Yeah, yeah!
- Yeah!
- Two, three.
♪ And that's our song ♪
♪ We hope that you enjoyed it ♪
♪ And if you thought that
it was stupid and trite ♪
♪ Come on and kill us with a forklift ♪
♪ All we wanna do, with
love from us to you ♪
♪ Is sing ♪
♪ The Fugitive Alien song ♪
- Muah!
- Yah, huh, huh!
- Hi-keeba!
(upbeat theme music)
- [Tom] No, no, you are Mr. Show Business.
(cross-talking)
- Smokin'.
- [Tom] Absolutely.
- Catchy.
(explosion booms)
- [Tom] Ooh.
Oh, no!
- Hey.
- [Tom] That big Mega
Servo just went up there.
- [Joel] Oh, no.
- [Tom] Doggone it.
- Oh, they blewed it up
before we found out what it was!
- Blewed?
- Blewed it up.
- [Tom] Now you see, this is
why we don't let teenagers
into hotels anymore.
This kinda stuff.
- [Crow] Especially New Kids.
- [Tom] Mm.
- (gasps) Look.
- Huh?
- Sir!
- All right!
(Joel chuckles mockingly)
- Terrific!
- Super, really super!
(explosions boom)
- Here it goes!
- [Tom] All right.
Ah, cherry, bar, cherry.
I haven't won all day.
(explosion booms)
- [Joel] We never found out
how big that thing was really.
- No.
- [Tom] No relative scale.
Wait, wait, what was the plot here?
I think they blew that up, too.
(Tom chuckles)
- It's Fahrvergnügen gone horribly wrong.
- [Tom] I'll say.
(snoring)
Know what this reminds me of?
Thunderbirds are go!
- Yup.
- [Tom] (chuckles) Remember?
- [Joel] Mm-hmm.
- That looks familiar.
- [Joel] Hey, do they have
another Herb Albert tape?
I'm really getting sick of this.
- [Tom] No, their 8-track recycled again.
- [Joel] You know, that
really does look good, though.
- It looks neat.
- Pretty impressive.
- Did Kissinger order this?
- [Tom] I think it was Schwarzkopf.
- Oh.
- [Joel] So there's stuff blowing up then.
- Pretty much.
- It's pretty neat.
- Kinda neat, yup.
- Yup.
- Blowin' it up.
- Yupper-doodle-doo.
- [Tom] Had some money to blow here.
- Oh, yeah.
- [Tom] (chuckles) It's sprinkle.
- [Joel] It does look good, though.
- Yeah, great.
- Really good.
- [Tom] Orgy of destruction,
always kinda fun.
- Sorry, everyone! Sorry!
Only meant to blow up that one thing.
Sorry.
- [Joel] It's the bridge on
the River Kwai over there.
(Tom whistles)
- Lower the bridge.
- [Tom] Yup.
- And they still haven't hit that.
- [Tom] Oh, here it goes.
Wuh-oh.
Next on MacGyver. (chuckles)
- Can't begin to tell you how proud
I am of you guys.
- 'Cause I'm drunk.
- Greatest crew a captain ever had.
(Tom chuckles mockingly)
- He's all right.
- Hey, Ken.
- Hm?
- [Joel] Pull my finger,
then do that funny face you do.
(chuckles)
(Tom chuckles mockingly)
- [Joel] Ha ha! Yeah.
- [Tom] Pull my finger, too.
I love it when they do that.
- See, it's all workin' out.
I wish your mother were here to see this.
(Tom sighs)
Hmm.
- [Tom] So--
(Joel yelps)
- Rangers!
- [Tom] Gene Simmons?
- A research center on Earth
has just developed a bomb that
can destroy a whole planet.
- And you guys can't cut a
simple stake and shrimp combo.
- We will gain control of that bomb,
and then Valna will dominate the universe.
- [Goons] Yes, master!
- [Joel] The University
of Wisconsin, Madison,
a traditional of excellence
for over 200 years.
- I've been waiting for you, Captain.
- Five neat guys and a girl.
- That's not very wise.
- We're at the Reynold's aluminum plant.
- It's too dangerous.
- [Woman] I'm sorry,
my father was detained.
- What?
- He wanted to welcome you.
- Mother!
- Hm?
- What?
- What's up, Ken?
- Who is that?
- He's tripping.
- Looked like my mother.
Why'd she run away?
- 'Cause she hated kids, maybe?
- Mother!
- Ooh.
- Hey, not so fast, Ken!
Take it easy.
You know you you haven't
seen her in several years.
- [Joel] Sounds like they're
playing the Godfather theme.
- But no one ever really proved it.
That's why I--
- Ken, snap out of it.
- [Tom] Come on, this is your mother now.
Try her out.
- We've been assigned to
escort this young lady.
- I beg your pardon.
- Hi-keeba.
- That's all right.
- The problem is my father.
Ever since he developed that bomb,
all sorts of people have
been threatening me.
- Look, sir.
(dramatic menacing music)
- [Tom] Huh?
Uh-oh.
- [Joel] We're being attacked
by models from Members Only!
(Tom sings along with score)
- [Rocky] Take cover!
(lasers fire)
- [Tom] Oh, no.
It's the Dave Clark Five
and they're being attacked
by Dino, Desi, and Billy!
- It's like one of those Obsession ads.
- [Tom] If this is love,
then find me guilty.
- Pretentious and dull.
- [Tom] Mm-hmm.
- [Joel] Hey, it's the
guys from Delta Epsilon!
- [Tom] Against the guys from Sigma Phi.
- This kinda stuff
always happens on campus.
- [Tom] Yeah.
- Those soldiers moved
faster than I expected.
- Yeah.
- [Tom] Guido Sarducci?
- The manufacture of my invention.
- [Joel] Sugar in this gum?
- Preserved on this microfilm.
- [Tom] So it doesn't
stick to dental work, eh?
- You mean this little film--
- Mm-hmm.
- Contains information on a bomb
powerful enough to blow
up the entire universe?
- No matter what happens to me, Captain,
this microfilm must not
fall into the wrong hands.
- Why are they meeting in the shower?
- Not to make this invention public.
- [Joel] By the way, you're
sitting on the urinal.
(Tom hums casually)
- Tammy's got a Weber cooker.
- There she is again!
(curious music)
- Mother!
Why does she always run away?
- [Tom] And why is she younger than me?
Uh-oh.
- [Joel] Oh, man, now he's outside.
I'd see this part of the movie
needs a strict rewrite.
- [Tom] It's a little weird.
- Hey, Mom!
Where'd ya get the meadow?
- [Tom] We're the catering squad.
Hi-keeba.
- Greetings from our headquarters.
We have orders to bring you there.
(grunting)
(worrying music)
- The captain's sportin'
a bike rack there.
- [Tom] Ooh! (chuckles)
- Tell your headquarters
they can forget their orders.
- Captain!
- [Joel] Ash Wednesday, Saysar style.
- [Tom] Dum dum!
- Ouch.
Filmed in Convolution-vision!
- [Tom] (chuckles) I'll say.
(panting)
(ship soaring)
- Oh, ah!
- Mother, come back!
- What in the Sam Scratch is goin' on?
- [Tom] This is an
entirely different movie
we're watching here.
- It was Halkon.
- [Tom] Who?
Fred Biletnikoff!
- Attack.
(beams fire)
- [Joel] Hey, this side
shoots to the left.
- [Tom] Yup, heavily sided.
- Ken.
- Where the hell did you come from?
- All three of them were
to be taken back to Valna.
- Valna?
- Get me a spoon.
- Halkon was going to
hold them as hostages.
Just a minute.
This lady can tell you the rest.
- [Tom] The rest of the story.
- Halkon made me do it.
- Page two.
- He wanted me to
infiltrate your operation
posing as Ken's mother!
- Then he was going to kill her.
- It's like Oedipus.
- I better pay Halkon a visit.
(sobbing)
- Ken.
- You're not going to Valna.
- Dressed like that.
- That's crazy!
- He's right, Ken!
- What other choice do I have?
- You could get a smaller belt buckle.
- No way.
- [Joel And Bots] Jose.
- It's gotta be me.
♪ It's just gotta be me ♪
- Accept no responsibility.
You'd be acting on your own, Ken.
All we can do is wish you good luck.
- [Joel] Maybe pack you a few
sandwiches, but that's it.
- [Tom] That'd be nice.
- He must be destroyed by a Star Wolf!
- You'll always be a Star Wolf.
- But never a star.
(Ken laughs)
- Is that so awful?
If I'm able to use my
strength for a good cause?
- I'm just doin' what
Jerry does for those kids!
- Don't be a fool.
- [Joel] Don't be a fool
with your life, Billy.
- Nobody admires me more than I do.
- [Tom] Billy's over there.
- But you're no match for Halkon.
- Don't be so sure.
Halkon trained me for
every sort of combat.
He taught me well.
- One thing that Halkon didn't teach you
was to fight as dirty as he does,
which is the reason why
you'd better take some Earthlings along.
- [Joel] 'Cause we're basically scum.
- That's exactly what I was thinking.
(upbeat theme music)
- [Tom] I wonder what the
king is drinking tonight.
(urgent music)
(panting)
(Tom pants mockingly)
Oh, another Orrin Hatch.
- No, this one's a Richard Hatch.
- [Tom] Oh!
(bots giggle)
- One wretched Star Wolf?
- [Joel] Two wretched Star Wolves?
- I don't see any danger in that.
He had a space escort with him?
What's become of the others?
- Well, we're trying
to locate them, master.
- He's cute.
- I want Watford dead!
- Every one of them!
If they're not dead by
nightfall, you'll die!
- Yes, master!
- Oh, he is cute.
- [Tom] Kinda looks like
Tammy Faye, I think.
- Star Wolf.
(groans)
(grunting)
- Looking for me?
(bots chuckle)
Hello, Star Wolf.
- Hello, Shirl.
- Halkon.
I promised I'd return
here to settle the score.
- [Joel] Uh, I believe it was 15-love?
Something like that?
- Don't move!
(chuckles)
(Tom chuckles)
- You know you can't
bring ourself to kill me.
- [Tom] I'm wearing my magic
rain cape and ski gloves.
- After all, Star Wolf,
I'm the one who created you.
Everything you are and
everything you know,
you learned from me.
- Yeah, yeah.
- [Joel] Well, everything I learned,
I learned in kindergarten.
- [Halkon] The courage
to pull that trigger.
- You're wrong.
Everything I learned from you was wrong.
- [Joel] Like three-card monte.
- Was evil.
Evil.
- Evil.
- Now I've seen another way of life.
A life that's honest and decent.
- I'm going to become a nun!
- And I've come back to
destroy you and your evil!
- Ness.
- [Tom] Thing.
- Now die!
- No, you're the one that's gonna die!
- [Tom] No, you're the
one who's gonna die!
No, it's you! No, you're
the one who's gonna!
Who's gonna die?
(grunts)
- [Joel] Maybe I am gonna die.
- Hi-keeba.
- [Tom] Now I want you
to sing like Tommy Tune.
(Crow mimics whimpering puppy)
- [Underling] Lord Halkon!
Bacchus!
Bacchus 3 is headed
straight for our fortress!
(lasers fire)
- [Tom] Boy, I'll say.
- [Joel] Kinda looks like Captain Joe's
in the bucket, you know?
- [Tom] Yep, yep, yep.
- Yeah, he's had a few.
- [Joel] It's the opening of Mannix.
- Sorry.
(Tom sings along with score)
(grunting)
- [Tom] That was convenient.
(struggling)
(grunting)
(Tom grunting along)
That's a good defensive move.
Somersaults.
(grunting)
- Ah-ha.
- Classic Mannix disarm.
- Halkon.
- Jackie Chan, he is not.
- Wait a minute, Star Wolf.
Why don't we discuss this?
- [Tom] Over a cocktail and some calamari.
- Put down that sword.
What's the good of killing me?
We can be allies. (chuckles)
(grunting)
- [Joel] My nut!
(explosion booms)
(grunting)
- [Tom] Ooh, big mistake.
- [Joel] You're dumber
than I thought, Ken.
(urgent music)
- Die, Star Wolf!
(fake mother grunts)
- [Tom] Oh, another one.
You know, women just shouldn't
hang around this guy.
- Mother!
- Thanks, substitute mom.
- Ken, listen.
I'm not your real mother--
- [Joel] But an incredible simulation.
- She's his sister.
- Don't die!
- [Joe] Ken!
- Hey, neat, where'd you
get the girl on a stick?
- [Joe] This must be Halkon's work.
- [Tom] Yes, notice the fine
detail, the craftsmanship.
- Look!
Halkon's getting away.
- No!
- [Joel And Bots] Yes!
- No, he's not!
(engine booms)
♪ Super car ♪
- This is it!
- [Tom] This is it, the night of nights.
No more rehearsing and nursing our parts.
(lasers fire)
- Oop, sorry.
(explosion booms)
- [Joel] Uh, this is Bernard
Shaw in downtown Bagtown.
I'm under a table, I'm ready, cam B.
- [Tom] No, that was George Bernard Shaw.
- [Joel] In Baghdad?
- [Tom] No, no.
So, uh, why do you think they're fighting
over a Heidelberg?
(grunting)
- [Joel] He's gotta go bad, that one.
- Puppet ships to the rescue!
(Tom sings theme)
(explosions boom)
♪ Tried to kill us with a forklift ♪
- [Tom] Woo!
- [Joel] Where have I seen this before?
- [Tom] Oh, I don't know.
Long time ago in a galaxy far, far away?
- [Joel] Yup, that's it.
- [Tom] Pretty much.
- Attack.
- [Tom] Oh, he's urging himself on.
Self-motivation.
- Now, die!
- [Joel] You die, Joe!
- [Halkon] You'll never
destroy me, Star Wolf.
- You can't destroy me, I quit!
(explosion booms)
- [Tom] Oh, well, this has
at least gotta slow it down.
I mean, please.
- Put a chink in his get along.
- [Joel] There goes old Maine.
The whole campus is gone now.
- Woo.
- [Tom] Chink in his get along?
(takes deep breath)
- Are you glad we're heading for earth?
- Yeah.
- [Crow] 'Cause they have dentists there.
- There's a girl I can hardly wait to see!
- [Joel] A girl, you switch-hitter, you.
- What's wrong with you, Ken?
I would have thought you'd be
a little more enthusiastic.
- Captain.
- [Tom] Gang.
- I've got something to tell you.
- [Tom] I want to be a woman.
- You guys--
- What?
- [Tom] No, no, no, no.
- It was great knowing you.
- It was?
- [Ken] I've gotta go back to Valna.
- [Joel] Yeah, we hear your theme song.
- Ken!
- What do you hope to accomplish there?
- [Tom] Well, he signed up
for a health club membership,
and should use the rest of it.
It was 18 months.
- The land destroyed.
- Perhaps I can help
build a new nation there.
A new civilization.
- So you think you can
change the world, do ya?
- That's an impossible job.
- You'd need 10 lifetimes to complete it.
Think it over!
- Why don't you just stick with us, Ken?
After all, you started
life as an Earthling.
- [Joel] Yeah, I'll get help.
Maybe some hire some staff, I dunno.
- And died there.
I want to finish their work.
- Well, it's not exactly on our way.
- [Joe] It's your decision.
- [Tom] Boy, his cheeks are huge.
- Good luck, Ken.
Star Wolf.
- [Joel] Thanks, I think.
(reverent music)
- I'll just shake your hand.
- But I won't kiss you.
- I don't like goodbyes.
(Tom sobs)
- Billy.
- Don't be a hero, man.
- It's been great.
- Thanks.
- Dan?
- [Tom] Or whatever your name is, new guy.
I think I woulda liked you.
- We been through a lot together.
- Yeah.
- Soul brother.
- Tammy?
I'll never forget you.
- [Tom] And I'll never forget you, um, uh,
oh, Ken.
Ooh, doll hands.
- Ah, grow up.
- [Joel] Hey, they're gonna
land on that bowling ball.
(Tom sings along with score)
(instruments beep)
(clicking)
- Ready now. Take off!
- Take off, hoser!
- [Tom] Woo!
(Tom yelps)
(Tom sings along with store)
- Goodbye, Star Wolf.
- Goodbye, Ken.
- Goodnight, sweet prince.
- [Joel] Oh, look at that suit.
What, is he going to be in
swing choir or something?
(Tom chuckles)
- And we have closure.
- Yay!
- Woo!
- [Tom] Woo woo woo!
(Crow whistles)
Fugitive Alien will be back
in Fugitive Alien Come Home,
Fugitive Alien III,
The Next Day, The Final Chapter, 3000.
- Uh, let's see here,
uh, Brewster's Millions.
Uh, Brian's Song.
- Oh, no, no, I couldn't handle
Brian's Song again, Crow.
When I saw that, I was
dewy-eyed for a week.
- Oh, it didn't effect me that way at all.
- Well, you know, I had some other things
going on in my life at the time--
- Hey, you guys, what're you doing?
- Oh, we're just looking
through Leonard Maltin's movie guide.
Uh, thinkin' of shooting the Mads a memo,
hoping that they'd welcome some input
on the experiment selection.
- Yeah, you know, they
don't have to all be as bad
as the one we saw today.
(Crow barks)
And maybe all our interests
can be served, gang.
It can be a win-win situation!
- I don't know about that.
The Mads seem to be pretty territorial
about stuff like that.
One thing you have to admit,
at the end of this movie,
that evil villain they had was, uh,
actually pretty evil, you know?
- Oh, you mean the one
with the heavy rouge?
- Yeah, and the face that was dipped
in a huge vat of whiteout?
- Yeah, that guy.
(Crow chuckles)
- I know what you mean, Joel.
He scared me so much
I almost started watching the movie.
- Yeah, well, he was kinda like somebody's
idea of everything evil all
rolled into one, you know.
- Ah, you got a point there, Joel.
Kind of brought together the
terrifying aspects of Nazis
and mimes!
- And Marsha Mason!
- Oh, or Marilyn Quayle!
- Oh, there you go!
- Well, listen, if you guys wanted to,
how would you make your
ultimate evil person?
Who would it be made up of?
- Hmm, let's see.
- I'd combine the Wolfman, and Mothra,
and the bad Lee Marvin from Cat Ballou!
- Oh, yeah, that's great!
Uh, I'd take Tom T. Hall, add Roy Clark,
and a little Donna Fargo!
- Oh, the possibilities.
Richard Nixon, Richard
III, and Keith Richards.
You know, but according to the
Fellowship of the White Boar,
Richard III was actually a
fine man and a good sovereign--
- I don't even really think of
Keith Richards as that evil.
- Oh, but he's so scary!
Oh!
- Richard Basehart, Richard
Basehart, and Richard Basehart!
- Uh, but, Gypsy, you
like Richard Basehart.
- Oh.
- That's nice, girl.
- That's really nice.
- How 'bout, uh, Howie Mandell,
David Brenner and Gallagher?
- Yeah, or David Brenner, Andy Rooney,
David Brenner and a ferret!
- Wow!
- That one stung.
- Personally, I hate Mondays.
- [Tom And Joel] Yeah.
- I know what you mean.
Anyway, I think we need
something kind of uplifting,
so I brought along these letters here.
- All right.
- This first one, let's put
that on still store, Cambot.
This first one comes from an
Eddie Hogan of New Jersey.
He writes, "Hello, my name is Eddie
"and I would like to join
your information club.
"As you can tell, I'm not very good,
"I do not have very good writing,
"and I'm already 13."
- Uh-oh.
- That's too bad.
- It's over.
- "I hate school, homework, teachers,
"and cheesy movies."
- Good, good attitude.
- Well, that's good.
- "I'm a big fan, and I
think you're all funny,
"even Gypsy.
"I watch your show on Saturdays,
"I would watch them Monday through Friday,
"but they're on at 10 AM and
I'm in school falling asleep."
(Tom chuckles nervously)
Well--
- That's nice.
- Let's get another one.
- That was really uplifting,
Joel, I gotta tell ya.
- This one seems happier.
Let's put this one up on still store.
Eddie, you might wanna get into breakfast.
- [Tom] Nice drawing, cool.
- Uh, anyway, this one
has Tom Servo saying,
"What are we cowboys?
"I'd like to shoot that intro."
And then Gypsy's there saying,
"Richard Basehart, RAM chips, huh?"
- Yup, that's her.
- And then Crow's saying, "Shut
up, I can't take any more!
"Get on with it already, jeez!"
And then it's got me saying, "Well,
"It can also double as a can opener."
And then it's got the Mads
saying, "File this, Frank."
And then Frank's saying, "I will.
"I will file this.
"I will file it."
- It's really a nice rendition
of Frank, too, isn't it?
- Yeah, it is.
It's pretty good.
- Yeah, those people weren't
evil at all, were they?
Oh, I came up with another one.
Coffee ice cream, paper
cuts, and Dan Haggerty!
(shouting)
- Oh, wow, you're just getting weird,
and that results in creativity.
What do you think, sirs?
- Well, Martin Buber, I
hardly think you're qualified
to be considering the
nature of evil. (chuckles)
Push the button, Frank.
- Hey, I like Tom T. Hall.
- Oh, Frank, think evil.
♪ I love baby ducks ♪
- Oh, Frank, you're just
embarrassing me now.
♪ Baby, kooky, kooky, kooky ♪
♪ Baby, baby ♪
(reverent organ music)
- (grunts) Captain!
I've got it fixed!
It's all working again!